MATTHEW R. R. WINEMILLER

Tucson, AZ 85747 • 520-977-9253 • mrrwmix@gmail.com • Digital portfolio: mrrwmix.github.io • LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/matthew-winemiller-27497b37/ • GitHub: https://github.com/Mrrwmix

CAREER SUMMARY

Full stack developer focused on teamwork and problem solving. Collaborating with all parties and keeping coworkers tuned into the task on hand comes from 5 years of teaching experience. The same amount of effort required of a Teacher of the Year Nominee from an A+ school will be applied to a future employer.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node, Sass, MongoDB, Firebase, GIT, GitHub, Bootstrap, APIs, AJAX, JSON, REST, MySQL, researching documentation, algorithms, tech support and computer science fundamentals.

APPLICATIONS BUILT

What Happened On...?

- A web app which makes requests to 4 different APIs based on a date entered
- JavaScript lead developer in a team of three
- Utilizes HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Sass, Material Design Lite
- https://mrrwmix.github.io/project1-ajgcmwmw/

Giftastic

- A web app which queries Giphy and utilizes local storage to save favorite gifs
- HTML, Bootstrap, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX
- https://mrrwmix.github.io/Giftastic/

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mesquite Elementary School, Tucson, AZ 2017 to 2019 4th Grade Teacher

- Recognized as the technical lead for the new 1:1 Chromebook program
- Teacher of the Year nominee at an A+ school
- Achieved math scores 35 percentage points higher than the state average

Chungdahm Learning and Chungdahm April, South Korea 2011 to 2014 **English Teacher**

- Taught all ages
- Students taught consistently tested above school average
- Developed plans with Korean co-teachers to reach every student effectively

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATES

Front End Libraries, https://freeCodeCamp.org	2019
Full Stack Certificate, The University of Arizona, Tucson	2019
JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures, https://freeCodeCamp.org	2019
Responsive Web Design, https://freeCodeCamp.org	2019
Elementary Teaching Certification, Pima Community College 2015 to	2016

Bachelor of Arts in Sociology, The University of Arizona, Tucson 2006 to 2010 Minor in Portuguese